Adrián López Calvo

Software Engineer

Calle Capitán Haya 13, 28020, Madrid, Madrid Spain

☑ adrian.lc.work@gmail.com
 ☐ +34 676 789 447
 in adrianlc
 ☑ AdrianLC
 ☑ AdrianLC



Experience mostly on *backend* web development and *Python's* ecosystem with a preference for open source tools. Things I love to work with include: APIs, testing, continuous integration, databases, performance tuning, *i18n* and more yet to discover!

SKILLS

Programming

Advanced

python | java | javascript | c | git | testing

Backend

Advanced

django | celery | sql | postgresql | mongodb | elasticsearch | web services | scrapping

DevOps

Intermediate

ansible | vagrant |
continuous integration |
amazon web services | apache |
ubuntu | fedora

Frontend

Beginner

html | django & jinja templates | css | angularjs | jquery

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Smartvel

October 2014 - Current

http://smartvel.com

Skills acquired: python | django | django-rest-framework | celery | django-haystack | postgresql | postgis | redis | mongodb | elasticsearch | ansible | vagrant | aws | angularjs

Built products of the company focusing mostly on backend and web development.

- Migrated the processing core to an asynchronous queue system with Celery.
- Managed the work queues: routing, priorities, monitoring, concurrency, autoscaling, deployments.
- Built a component to translate texts, obtained through scrapping, automatically.
- Implemented several tools to improve names and boundaries in the geographic data.
- Maintained geographic boundaries with QGIS and shapefiles.
- Set up the MongoDB server with Ansible.
- Handled several major upgrades such as: MongoDB 2 to 3, Django 1.7 to 1.9 or Rest Framework 2 to 3.
- Optimized critical SQL queries, including Postgresql extensions such as postgis, trigrams and full text search.

Web Development Intern at Arantia, Televés Corp

August 2013 - September 2013

http://www.arantia.com

Skills acquired: javascript | php | html | css | html5-canvas

Worked on several bugs and tasks in the software internal to an IPTV solution.

- Integrated some Javascript/HTML5 Canvas games with the set-top box and its remote control.
- Renewal of the user interface for set-top box settings.

EDUCATION

BS Computer Science at Universidade de Santiago de Compostela

2009 - 2013

Major courses: oo programming | data structures & algorithms | software engineering | operative systems | networks | system administration | web development | soap web services | distributed computing

LANGUAGES

Spanish native speaker

English advanced

Galician
native speaker

REFERENCES

Available upon request.